Fei Zhang

Software engineer

Skills

Programming Languages
TypeScript, JavaScript, Nodejs,
Html&css, Sass, Less, GraphQL

Libraries & Frameworks
Next.js, React, jQuery, Express,
TailwindCSS, Styled
Components, Ant Design, MUI,
Storybook

Tools & Platforms Git, Webpack, AWS, Docker, Vercel, Strapi, Sanity, Sentry

Languages

English

Mandarin

Projects

Headless CMS Blog, using aws & vercel to deploy strapi and website separately

Education

Bachelor Degree, History, Sichuan University

Profile

When I was a senior CMS manager 6 years ago, I made this career transition to become a software developer. I love getting hands-on with Tech, and I have found that working as a software developer, I get more exposure and hands-on with technology than any other role I have experienced. I don't personally see the previous time as wasted though as it gave me an invaluable insight into CMS industry.

Employment History

Software engineer, Freelance

July 2023 to date

 Building applications in my personal time. Full stack apps using a mix of the following tech: React, NextJS, Typescript, GraphQL, Styled Components & TailwindCSS, Strapi, AWS(EC2, RDS, S3), NodeJS, Git, VS Code

Front End Developer, Duozhuayu, Beijing

Oct 2022 - June 2023

- The toC user interface using react, typescript, styled components to build responsive UI with Storybook, using axios to fetch data and redux to manage the state. The inhouse CMS system using react & typescript & ant-design & redux to manage the warehouse stock.
- Working with a dev team of 10 people, mutually review code and address pr feedbacks, split tasks and assign to team members regularly.

Front End Developer, UC Browser, Beijing

June 2018 - Sep 2022

- Writing modern, performant, maintainable code for multiple content management systems.
- Using different languages, frameworks, and libraries such as JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux, Ant Design, Styled Components, Node.js, WebSocket.
- Communicating with multi-disciplinary teams of engineers, product managers on a regular basis.
- Providing effective troubleshooting and remediation for web applications.

Content Operation Manager, Toutiao, Beijing

Dec 2014 - May 2018

- Select breaking news and high-quality content, utilize advanced personalized recommendation technology to deliver to users, making our APP the most popular news app in China.
- Collaborate with product and development teams to create new consumer products and build internal operational tools.
- Responsible for discussing with UI & UX about then content display and user interaction of website content, using sketches and Lark, etc.

Content Operations, NetEase, Beijing

July 2011 - Nov 2014

 Writing and publishing news and anecdotes around the world on website, also dealing with comments and interact with viewers.